Finding Aid for Charles L. Follo papers, 1961-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles L. Follo papers 1961-1970
Follo, Charles L.
4 linear feet
851297 Aa 2
Delegate to the Michigan Constitutional Convention of 1961-1962; diary, correspondence, and topical files from his work as delegate; Human Resources Council of the Upper Peninsula Committee for Area Programs chairman’s files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Charles Follo (donor no. 2882 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Charles Follo was assistant director of University of Michigan Extension Service for programs in the Upper Peninsula. In addition he served as delegate to the Michigan Constitutional Convention of 1961-1962 and chairman of the Human Resources Council of the Upper Peninsula Committee for Area Programs.
The collection consists of three series: Constitutional Convention Delegate File; Upper Peninsula Committee for Area Progress (UPCAP) Human Resources Council papers; and University of Michigan Extension Service. The bulk of the collection relates to the constitutional convention and includes a diary of his convention experiences, correspondence with constituents and interest groups, and subject files on the issues discussed at the convention. Some of his correspondents included Alvin M. Bentley, Prentiss M. Brown, and Neil Staebler.
Subjects:
Bentley, Alvin M. (Alvin Morell), 1918-1969.; Brown, Prentiss Marsh, 1889-1973.; Labor supply--Michigan--Upper Peninsula.; Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1961-1962); Michigan Library Association.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Staebler, Neil, 1905-; University of Michigan. Extension Service.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.
- Constitutional Convention Delegate File
  - Diary, October 1, 1961-May 11, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Papers, July 26, 1961-January 31, 1961, 41 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers, February 1, 1962-1963, 31 folders (Box 2)
  - Topical files (largely concerning Constitutional Convention)
    - Education, undated, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Local Government, undated, 7 folders (Box 2)
    - Taxation and Finance (Box 2)
    - Committee proposals and amendments (Box 2)
    - Rules and procedures of the convention, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Judicial branch (Box 3)
    - Executive branch (Box 3)
    - Legislative branch, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Bibliographies (Box 3)
    - Lists of delegates, committee assignments, and election results (Box 3)
    - Democratic Party and Con-Con (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Address to the People (tentative draft) (Box 3)
- Upper Peninsula Committee for Area Progress (UPCAP); Human Resources Council
  - Topical files, 1966-1970
    - Alcoholism Committee, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Community Health and Mental Health (Box 3)
    - Cultural activities, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Economic opportunity (Box 3)
    - Education
      - Conference on Education (Box 3)
      - Elementary and Secondary Education Act (Box 3)
      - School District Reorganization (Box 3)
      - Vocational education (Box 3)
    - Housing (Box 4)
    - Human resources, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Upper Peninsula Committee for Area
      - Problems (later Area Progress) (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous files, 1963-1970, 4 folders (Box 4)
- University of Michigan Extension Service
  - Upper Peninsula Office
    - Printed material (Box 4)